Register of the David Benjamin Bolen Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Albums,., 1946-2001 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, (unnumbered)., 1963-1997 (Box 41)
    - Remarks on the occasion of the signing of the U.S.-GDR Consular Convention,., 1979 September 4 (Folder 41: 9)
    - Address on East-West relations,., 1980s (Folder 41: 10)
    - "Implications of Internal/External Environment for Strategic Planning," course lecture,., 1980s (Folder 41: 11)
    - "U.S.-GDR Perspectives in East-West Relations,"., 1980 June 18 (Folder 41: 12)
    - "U.S. Relations with Eastern Europe in a Changing World," DePaul University, Chicago, Illinois,., 1980 August 27 (Folder 41: 13)
    - "Change, Challenge and Opportunity in the World of Work," 14th Annual College/Industry Relations Conference, Norfolk, Virginia,., 1982 January 25 (Folder 41: 14)
    - "Managing Cultural Conflict in an Interdependent World," First Annual Charter Dinner, Delaware Chapter, People to People International,., 1985 September 11 (Folder 41: 15)
    - "International Business Against Apartheid: Toward Optimum Resource Development," International Conference on South Africa: The Process and Prospects of Creating a Nonracial, Democratic Nation of South Africa, Baruch College, New York,., 1987 September 29-October 2 (Folder 41: 16)
      Printed copy
    - "German Unification: Defense or Détente," keynote address, American/German Chamber of Commerce, Denver, Colorado,., 1996 October 3 (Folder 41: 17)
    - "U.S. Foreign Service: The German Case," Fairview High School, Boulder, Colorado,., 1996 November 26 (Folder 41: 18)
  - Unnumbered,., 1978-2003 (Folder 41: 19)
    Materials relating to Bolen's diplomatic and business careers, consisting primarily of correspondence and clippings. Includes printed copy of an article on Ambassador Bolen from the Sunday Camera, Boulder, Colorado, 2002 February 14, and an inventory of the collection prepared by Bolen
- Oversize Materials,., 1950-1994 (Box 42)
  Certificates, clippings, and photographs, arranged alphabetically by physical form and thereunder chronologically
  - Certificates of appointment received by David S. Bolen, 1950-1977
    - Vice Consul of the United States at Monrovia, Liberia, 1950 April 6 (Folder 42: 1)
    - Foreign Service Officer, Class Five, 1955 June 15 (Folder 42: 2)
    - Secretary in the Diplomatic Service, 1955 June 15 (Folder 42: 3)
    - Vice Consul of Career, 1955 June 15 (Folder 42: 4)
    - Foreign Service Officer, Class Five, 1957 January 29 (Folder 42: 5)
    - Consul, 1957 January 29 (Folder 42: 6)
    - Foreign Service Officer, Class Four, 1960 March 18 (Folder 42: 7)
    - Foreign Service Officer, Class Three, 1965 May 26 (Folder 42: 8)
    - Consular Officer, 1970 February 17 (Folder 42: 9)
    - United States Ambassador to Botswana, 1974 February 28 (Folder 42: 10)
    - United States Ambassador to Lesotho, 1974 February 28 (Folder 42: 11)
    - United States Ambassador to Swaziland, 1974 February 28 (Folder 42: 12)
    - Deputy Assistant Secretary of State, 1976 August 12 (Folder 42: 13)
    - United States Ambassador to the German Democratic Republic, 1977 July 29 (Folder 42: 14)
  - Clippings,., 1979-1994 (Folder 42: 15)
    Photocopies of articles about Erich Honecker from the American and East German press
  - Photographs,., 1989 (Folder 42: 16)
    One print depicting a scene at the Berlin Wall immediately prior to its demolition, and a color photocopy reproducing a series of photographs depicting the demolition of the Berlin Wall
- Incremental Materials,., 1979 (Box 42)
  Correspondence, arranged chronologically
  - Unclassified cables sent to the State Department by Ambassador Bolen concerning his meetings with Herman Axen and Günter Mittag, members of the East German politburo, 1979 January 22 (Folder 42: 17)